Mss.Rec.68 Mss.Rec.68
American Philosophical Society
- Audio recordings
  - Dance (?) Song for Potlatch at Batzulnitas, 1916-18?, 1968-08-22; 22-12; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:41; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha; Justin, Jack John; Pete, Elizabeth; Pete, Mentasta; Stanfield, Fanny
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena language; Copper Center (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Dance; Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Potlatch--Alaska
  - Another Shushana Song, for entering dance hall, 1968-08-22; 22-13; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:56; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha; Justin, Jack John; Pete, Elizabeth; Pete, Mentasta; Stanfield, Fanny
  - Whitehorse, Yukon Territory song, 1968-08-22; 22-14; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:46; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha; Justin, Jack John; Pete, Elizabeth; Pete, Mentasta; Stanfield, Fanny
    Song repeated by request Frederica de Laguna.
  - Mentasta Pete's Half-brother's Sorry Song for His Older Brother, 1968-08-22; 22-15; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:12; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha; Pete, Mentasta
  - Potlatch Calls: Crows and Seagulls Eating, 1968-08-22; 22-16; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:08; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha; Justin, Jack John; Pete, Elizabeth; Pete, Mentasta; Stanfield, Fanny
  - Knik Indian (Dasnei) Song "ehey...uley...diqaqeni", 1968-08-22; 22-17; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:08; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha; Justin, Jack John; Pete, Elizabeth; Pete, Mentasta; Stanfield, Fanny
    Singing led by Martha Jackson after attempt by Mentasta Pete to begin song.
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Copper Center (Alaska); Dena'ina language; Indians of North America--Alaska--Music
  - Knik Indian Paddling Song: "ye he ha we'eli ha", 1968-08-22; 22-18; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:03; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha; Justin, Jack John; Pete, Elizabeth; Pete, Mentasta; Stanfield, Fanny
  - Another Knik Indian Paddling Song: "ye yalei", 1968-08-22; 22-19; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:02; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha; Justin, Jack John; Pete, Elizabeth; Pete, Mentasta; Stanfield, Fanny
  - Forbidden Dance Song, 1968-08-22; 22-20; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:46; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha; Justin, Jack John; Pete, Elizabeth; Pete, Mentasta; Stanfield, Fanny
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena language; Copper Center (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Dance; Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Taboo
  - Knik Indian Worry Song: "vita yeya...ye do du 'iti tige", 1968-08-22; 22-21; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:41; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha; Pete, Mentasta
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Copper Center (Alaska); Dena'ina language; Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Mourning customs--United States--Alaska
  - Tenas Waski (Prohibition Song), 1968-08-22; 22-22; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:14; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha; Pete, Elizabeth; Stanfield, Fanny
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Copper Center (Alaska); Drinking songs; Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Prohibition--Songs and music; Tlingit language
  - Snatch of TcElali Drinking Song, 1968-08-22; 22-23; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:27; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha; Justin, Jack John; Pete, Elizabeth; Pete, Mentasta; Stanfield, Fanny
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena language; Copper Center (Alaska); Drinking songs; Indians of North America--Alaska--Music
  - Goodby Song: "hey e sudE", 1968-08-22; 22-24; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:32; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha; Justin, Jack John; Pete, Elizabeth; Pete, Mentasta; Stanfield, Fanny
  - Cries for Calico Tug-of-War, 1968-08-22; 22-25; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:26; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena language; Copper Center (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Tug of war (Game)
  - Boreal Owl (laitcI') Song, when he wants to get moose, 1968-08-23; 23-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:56; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Ewan, Oscar
    Recording begins with introduction to recording session by Frederica de Laguna.
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena language; Gulkana (Alaska); Hunting songs; Indians of North America--Alaska--Music
  - Henry Joe's Hard Luck Song (sorry for loss of father), Nenana (heard in 1916), 1968-08-23; 23-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:09; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Ewan, Oscar
    Song followed by explanation of song in English.
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Gulkana (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Mourning customs--United States--Alaska; Tanana language
  - Oscar Ewan's Own Sorry Song for his Oldest Son, 1968-08-23; 23-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:34; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Ewan, Oscar
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena language; Gulkana (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Mourning customs--United States--Alaska
  - Fred Ewan's Sorry Song for his Father, 1953-54 (?), 1968-08-23; 23-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:24; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Ewan, Oscar
  - Tlingit Dance Song: "ali la ye i. ye i. li ya", 1968-08-23; 23-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:14; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Ewan, Oscar
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Gulkana (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Dance; Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Tlingit language
  - Old Time Copper River Dance Song (prob. Tlingit) "ya lastu 'hi eli ya las", 1968-08-23; 23-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:41; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Ewan, Oscar
  - Victory Song for War with Aleuts, 1968-08-23; 23-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:55; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Ewan, Oscar
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena language; Aleuts; Gulkana (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; War songs
  - Joe Goodlataw's "Grandfather's" (mother's father's brother's) Sorry Song for Joe's great(?) grandfather who drowned. TurAl. "ayo heye hey hayo hayu", 1968-08-24; 23-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:47; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Goodlataw, Joe; Goodlataw, Martha
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena language; Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Lower Tonsina (Alaska); Mourning customs--United States--Alaska
  - Two Tlingit Dance Songs, 1968-08-24; 23-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:49; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Goodlataw, Joe; Goodlataw, Martha
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Indians of North America--Alaska--Dance; Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Lower Tonsina (Alaska); Tlingit language
  - Bill Joe's Own Dance Song, composed 2 days before, 1968-08-29; 23-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:04; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill
    Recording begins with introduction to recording session by Frederica de Laguna. Song is played twice.
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena language; Indians of North America--Alaska--Dance; Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Lower Tonsina (Alaska)
  - Oscar Ewan's Sorry Song for his Son, 1968-08-29; 23-11; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:04; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena language; Chistochina (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Mourning customs--United States--Alaska
  - Martha Jackson's Mother's Love Song for Mentasta Sam, 1968-08-29; 23-12; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:38; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie
  - Steven John's Mother's Love Song, Gulkana, 1968-08-29; 23-13; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:44; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie
  - Snatch of Song by Long Lucy, 1968-08-29; 23-14; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:16; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; John, Lucy
  - Sourdough Gene's Love Song, for his girl who left while he slept, 1968-08-29; 23-15; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:57; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill
  - Sourdough Gene's Love Song "ha 'engi ye da 'ni hi", 1968-08-29; 23-16; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:51; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill
  - Fred John's Sister's Sorry Song for her Father, Mentasta [1 of 2], 1968-08-29; 23-17; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:01; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie
  - Fred John's Sister's Sorry Song for her Father, Mentasta [2 of 2], 1968-08-29; 23-18; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:07; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie
  - Mrs. Mentasta Bob's Sorry Song for her Song, Suslota, 1968-08-29; 23-19; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:38; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie
  - Alice Stickwan's Father's Sleep Doctor Song, 1968-08-29; 23-20; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:47; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena language; Chistochina (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Shamanism--Alaska
  - Tanacross Dance Song, 1968-08-29; 23-21; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:36; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Chistochina (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Dance; Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Tanacross language
  - Up-the-Line Dance Song, 1968-08-29; 23-22; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:00; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill
  - Up-the-Line Dance Song, 1968-08-29; 23-23; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:37; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie
  - Titus John's Song about Drunken Men like Muskrats, 1968-08-29; 23-24; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:38; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill
  - Mrs. Yusti Sanford's Whiskey Song, 1968-08-29; 23-25; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:36; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill
  - Up-the-Line Whiskey Song, 1968-08-29; 23-26; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:44; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie
  - Gallon of Wine, 1968-08-29; 23-27; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:47; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie
  - I'm going to see you again, 1968-08-29; 23-28; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:48; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill
  - Tanacross Song, 1968-08-29; 24-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:31; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie
  - Santa Claus Song, sung when Santa comes through the door, 1968-08-29; 24-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:35; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena language; Christmas music; Copper Center (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Santa Claus--Songs and music
  - "Ha, Christmas Tree!" Song, 1968-08-29; 24-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:29; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Christmas trees--Songs and music; Copper Center (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music
  - Christmas Day song, 1968-08-29; 24-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:44; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena language; Christmas music; Copper Center (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music
  - Yo yEga 'ayi, 1968-08-29; 24-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:31; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill
  - U hu 'eye heya, 1968-08-29; 24-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:47; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill
  - Up-the-Line Song, 1968-08-29; 24-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:54; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill
  - North Country Dance Song, 1968-08-29; 24-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:39; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill
  - Dance Song, composed by Walter Northway, when at a potlatch at Tanacross, 1968-08-29; 24-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:28; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Copper Center (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Dance; Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Potlatch--Alaska; Upper Tanana language
  - Dance Song by Copper Gene and Copper Jack: "tletiko", 1968-08-29; 24-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:50; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill
    Song identified by Copper Lily of Burwash Landing, Yukon, as a potlatceh song by her father, Copper Jack, a Southern Tutchone speaker.
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Copper Center (Alaska); Indians of North America--Canada--Dance; Potlatch; Southern Tutchone language
  - Song by Copper Jack, 1968-08-29; 24-11; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:33; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill
  - Song about Nabesna: "Why do you want us to come down", 1968-08-29; 24-12; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:41; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill
    Collector's docuemation identifies as possibliy being composed by Copper Jack, a Southern Tutchone speaker.
  - Copper Jack's Song: "Why you want us to come down?", 1968-08-31; 24-13; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:38; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Jessie; Lily, Copper; TomTom, Joe; Watt, Sophie
    Burwash Landing (Yukon); Indians of North America--Canada--Music; Southern Tutchone language; Tutchone Indians--Music
  - Song by Sophie Watt, 1968-08-31; 24-14; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:52; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Watt, Sophie
  - Song composed by Old Man Johnson, 1968-08-31; 24-15; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:06; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Jessie; McClellan, Catharine; Watt, Sophie
  - Mackenzie Indians' Gambling Song, 1968-08-31; 24-16; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:33; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; TomTom, Joe
    The language of this song is not identified in the collector's documentation. Its identification as a "Mackenzie Indian" song indicates that its language is most likely North Slavey.
    Burwash Landing (Yukon); Indians of North America--Canada--Music; Slave Indians--Music; Slave Indians--Social life and customs; Slave language; Tutchone Indians--Music
  - Jessie Joe dictates a message in Athabaskan to Maggie Jim at 1016 (Haines Junction), ending with a song, 1968-08-31; 24-17; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:56; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Jessie
  - Emma Johnson's own Hudson's Bay Love Song, 1968-08-31; 24-18; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:11; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Jessie
    Burwash Landing (Yukon); Indians of North America--Canada--Music; Love songs; Southern Tutchone language; Tutchone Indians--Music
  - Songs by Sophie Watt and Jessie Joe, 1968-08-31; 24-19; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:49; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Jessie; Watt, Sophie
  - Potlatch given by Titus David for his father Chief David, who died in 1923 [1 of 2], 1966-11-26; 25-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:30:05; David, Titus; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Jimmy
    This potlatch was recorded in Tetlin, Alaska by Jimmy Joe. Copies of the recording were later given to Frederica de Laguna. A detailed list of the songs performed has not been located among the collector's documentation. Given the location of the recording, a significant portion of the songs are likely in the Upper Tanana language. Performance may include songs in languages of other nearby communities, though specific linguistic information is not available in the collector's documentation.
    Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Potlatch--Alaska; Tanana Indians--Music; Tanana Indians--Social life and customs; Tetlin (Alaska); Upper Tanana language
  - Potlatch given by Titus David for his father Chief David, who died in 1923 [2 of 2], 1966-11-26; 26-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:28:18; David, Titus; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Jimmy
  - Potlatch given for Henry John, who died May 20, 1968, 27-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:38:56; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Jimmy
  - Potlatch given for Chief Luke, Chief Peter, and Roosevelt Titus by Jimmy Joe, Titus David, and Emma Titus [1 of 2], 1963-11-29; 27-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:23:51; David, Titus; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Jimmy; Titus, Emma
  - Potlatch given for Chief Luke, Chief Peter, and Roosevelt Titus by Jimmy Joe, Titus David, and Emma Titus [2 of 2], 1963-11-29; 28-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:44:32; David, Titus; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Jimmy; Titus, Emma
  - Indian Party #2 at Tetlin in spring of 1961 for Martha Luke, 28-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:11:00; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Jimmy
    This performance was recorded in Tetlin, Alaska by Jimmy Joe. Copies of the recording were later given to Frederica de Laguna. A detailed list of the songs performed has not been located among the collector's documentation. Given the location of the recording, a significant portion of the songs are likely in the Upper Tanana language. Performance may include songs in languages of other nearby communities, though specific linguistic information is not available in the collector's documentation.